(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
またやった、俯いたまんまのな
Did it again, head hanging low.
泣きそうな顔見ていた
I was looking at that face, on the verge of tears.
「諦めないでよ」みたいな
Words like "Don't give up"...
言葉じゃ全然足りない！
...aren't nearly enough!
そしたらもっと元気を出さなきゃ
So you've gotta cheer up more!
明日も暗いままっすよ
Or else tomorrow will be dark, too!
君を連れ出して行く
I'll take you out of here...
無理矢理かなあ
...even if I have to force you?
日差しにブルーになる
Feeling blue in the sunlight...
君のことやっぱ正直心配だ
To be honest, I'm worried about you.
瞳が潤んでいく
Your eyes are welling up...
弱虫な僕には
...and for a coward like me...
ダメだよ、きっと
...it's no good, I'm sure.
だけど信じる君だから
But because it's you, who I believe in...
真っ直ぐ前を向いて
...keep looking straight ahead!
本当にダメな時は
When it's really too much for you...
君の心を支えてあげる
...I'll support your heart.
「いっそ」なんて諦めちゃ
Thinking "might as well give up"...
絶対ダメだからね
...is absolutely out of the question!
一緒に進もう
Let's move forward together!
独りぼっちを壊しちゃえ、ほら！
Break through that loneliness, come on!
どうなっちゃったか分からない
I don't know what happened...
君はまだ泣きそうだ
...but you still look like you're about to cry.
溜息ばっかで目を...
Sighing away, you close your eyes...
じゃあほら
So, look,
絶対絶命！
Absolute desperation!
もっとパンパン弾け飛ぶ思いも
Even thoughts popping and bursting more and more
昨日に冷えちゃって
Were chilled by yesterday,
街を駆け出していく無理な涙も
Along with forced tears as I run through the town.
夕暮れブルーになる
The evening turns blue,
夕立が閉ざしたその一瞬で
In that moment closed off by a sudden shower.
たちまち泣いた顔
Suddenly a crying face,
音もなく涙が
Without a sound, tears...
こぼれて消えた
...fell and vanished.
一つ小さいこの世界が
This one small world
大きく牙を剥いて
Bares its fangs wide,
「一緒にいたかったな」と
Saying, "I wanted to be with you,"
君の心をうつむかせる
Making your heart hang its head.
小さな言葉じゃもう
Even if small words
全然届かないとしても
Won't reach at all anymore,
「力になりたい」と
Saying, "I want to be your strength,"
助けたいんだよ。笑ってよ。
I want to help. Come on, smile.
信じる君だから
Because it's you, who believes,
本気の声出して
Give it your all and shout out,
「絶対ダメなんかじゃない！」
"It's definitely not hopeless!"
君が望めば、また出会える
If you wish for it, we can meet again.
大きな深呼吸で
With a big, deep breath,
遠くのお月様に
To the moon far away,
弱気な君が「やってやるさ！」と
Your timid self shouted out, "I'll do it!"
叫んでいた
Shouting out,
少しカッコいいかな。まあ。
Is that a bit cool? Well.
恋空予報
Love Sky Forecast
ドキドキドキドキしちゃってる
My heart is thumping, thumping,
あいつは全然気付かないな
That guy doesn't notice at all.
本当はもっと話したいのに
Even though I really want to talk more,
しつこいなんて思われてもな
What if he thinks I'm persistent?
授業中も上の空だし
Even during class, my mind is elsewhere,
こんなの悔しいけど仕方ないな
This is frustrating, but I can't help it.
恋空予報　叶わないかも
Love sky forecast, it might not come true,
晴れのち曇りで雨が降るでしょう
Fine, later cloudy, it will probably rain.
あいつの笑顔を
At that guy's smile,
いつも見とれて
I'm always staring,
私に本日恋してる模様
It seems I'm in love today.
ほらほらまたまたしてるでしょ
Look, look, you're doing it again, aren't you?
あっと言う間にあいつは帰るぞ
In the blink of an eye, that guy is going home!
今までずっと言えなかったけど
I haven't been able to say it until now,
本当はずっと好きだったから
But the truth is, I've always liked you.
答えは待って　すぐに言わないで
Wait for the answer, don't say it right away,
耳を塞ぎたくて　ただ怖くて
I want to plug my ears, I'm just scared.
恋空予報　叶えてお願い
Love sky forecast, please come true,
雨が降ってるけど一緒に帰ろう
It's raining, but let's go home together.
あいつの言葉を
That guy's words,
いつも思い出して
I always remember,
私に明日も恋してる模様
It seems I'll be in love tomorrow, too.
遠くにかかる虹
A rainbow spanning in the distance,
ふわり混ざる夕日
Softly blending with the sunset,
傘をたたんで
Folding the umbrella,
手を繋いだ
We held hands.
幸せもの　今日も恋空予報
Happy person, today's love sky forecast again,
これからもきっと晴れのち空
From now on, it'll surely be fine skies.
...ひとりで歩いてけるでしょう
...I can walk alone, right?
あのいつもの笑顔を
That usual smile
あのいつも見てて
Looking at that as always
私 本日恋してる模様
I seem to be in love today
ずっとこのまま恋してたい
I want to keep being in love like this
私
Me
みんなー！こんぺこ！こんぺこ！
Everyone! Kon-peko! Kon-peko!
こんぺこー！
Kon-peko!
このライブ 3周年の兎田ぺこら...
This live, 3rd anniversary Usada Pekora...
ヤッホーヤッホーヤッホー！見てるぺこか？
Yaho-yaho-yaho! Are you watching, peko?
ありがとう！
Thank you!
どうぺこだった？
How was it, peko?
まずはお月見リサイタルと恋空予報、2曲！
First, 'Otsukimi Recital' and 'Love Sky Forecast', two songs!
やったぺこ！どうぺこですか？可愛いぺこか？
I did it, peko! How was it? Am I cute, peko?
可愛かった？
Was I cute?
おめでた、ありがとう！今日は本当に...
Thanks for the congrats! Today is really...
兎田ぺこらの生誕祭ライブ来ていただき...
Thank you so much for coming to...
まことに、まことにありがとうございます！
Usada Pekora's birthday live!
そして今Twitterね、ぜひ兎田ぺこら生誕祭で...
And on Twitter, please use #UsadaPekoraBirthday...
たくさん呟いていただけたら嬉しいぺこだな...
I'd be happy if you tweet a lot, peko...
なんて思いますので、どうぞどうぞ...
So please, please...
たくさん呟いてほしいなと思うぺこです。
I hope you tweet a lot, peko.
ま、なんでまだぺこらがこの昔の状態の...
Well, you might wonder why I'm still in this old...
ぺこらだと思って... これもめちゃめちゃ可愛いぺこだけどね。
...Pekora form. This one is also super cute, peko.
でもみんな多分気になっていると思う。
But everyone is probably curious.
一肌脱いだ兎田ぺこらが観たいと。
You want to see Usada Pekora shed her skin.
アップデートした兎田ぺこらを観たい？
Want to see the updated Usada Pekora?
観たい？可愛いしか流れてない、ありがとぺこな。
Want to see? Only 'cute' is in the chat, thanks peko.
おめでとうありがとう、トレンド入りありがとう！
Thanks for the congrats, and for trending!
もっとたくさん呟いて、もっともっともっと...
Tweet more, keep it going more and more...
乗せてぺこな。あ、観たい！
...peko. Ah, you want to see!
じゃあ仕方ないぺこだな。
Well, I guess I have no choice, peko.
じゃあ、アップデートした兎田ぺこらを...
Then, I'll debut the updated Usada Pekora...
あの曲で披露したいと思うぺこだから...
...with that song, peko...
ちょっと準備してくるから待っててね！
So I'll go get ready, wait a bit!
すぐぺこだから！じゃね！ちょっと待ってて！
It'll be quick, peko! See ya! Wait a bit!
お化粧しなきゃ、急げ急げ！
Need to do makeup, hurry hurry!
ランダムぺこは叫んじゃえは
Shout out the random-peko
事件だ毎日だ hey
It's a case, every day, hey
大正解このためだと 笑えない情なく笑え
If this is the right answer, laugh without a trace
ぺこらんだむーむーむーむーか
Pekorandom-m-m-m-ka
ぺこらんだむ起死回生
Pekorandom revival
no no no no 次第主変えや
No no no no, change the owner
no no no no stay na na na na
no no no no 次第主変えや
No no no no, change the owner
受け取り飛びれるぞ
I can take it, it's jumping!
難題外な touch and go
Unlikely touch and go
ぴゅんとプロペラ回れ
Spin the propeller with a zoom
どこへ向かうか知らない
Don't know where it's headed
知らないんだ
I just don't know
なんて世界は繋がっちゃう
What a world, it just connects
なんて超えたら銀河系
Crossing over to the galaxy
なんで会いたいって思うんだ
Why do I want to see you?
そんなのどうでもいいじゃん いいじゃん
That doesn't matter, it's fine, it's fine
退屈嫌だったら こっち来れば
If you're bored, come over here
大事な場所なんてさ 自分で作らなくちゃ
Important places must be made by yourself
それぞ絶叫だ どだどだどだ
That's a scream, it's... it's...
ありがとう言いましたか？
Did you say thank you?
ランダムぺこはびっくりだわ
Surprised by random-peko
生きてや毎日だ hey
Keep living, every day, hey
大問題の後には 楽しいことあるから
After big problems, there are fun things
ランダムぺこは叫んじゃえは
Shout out the random-peko
事件だ毎日だ hey
It's a case, every day, hey
大正解このためだと 笑えない情なく笑え
If this is the right answer, laugh without a trace
ぺこらんだむーむーむーむーか
Pekorandom-m-m-m-ka
ぺこらんだむ起死回生
Pekorandom revival
no no no no 次第主変えや
No no no no, change the owner
no no no no stay na na na na
no no no no 次第主変えや
No no no no, change the owner
受け取り飛びれるぞ
I can take it, it's jumping!
どんな空でも hero we go
Whatever the sky, hero we go
ふわり期待の回る
Softly expectation spins
どっちが地面か知らない
Don't know which is the ground
染みたくーな
Don't want to freeze
ドッパしてるって 褒めて来れば？
Why don't you praise me for breaking through?
どうもならない寄り道さ
An unavoidable detour
誰か会いたいって言ってよ
Someone say they want to see me
エブリタイム　ウレシーカラネ　ヤッホヤッホ
Every time, because I'm happy, yaho yaho!
冒険選ぶなら　こっち来れば
If you choose adventure, come over here
まずは一歩目からだ
Start with the first step
千はちょっと無理だろ
A thousand is a bit too much, right?
ヤバい　ごめんね　待って待って待って
Oh no, sorry, wait wait wait!
思わず出ちゃったよ
It just came out
ペコランダム　ほら踊れば
Pecorandom, look, if you dance
めちゃくちゃヤセるかな？
Will I lose a lot of weight?
ダイバンザイ大好き
I love the big cheers
楽しいなら大好き
If it's fun, I love it
ペコランダム　歌っちゃえば
Pecorandom, if I sing
まだまだヤセちゃうかな？
Will I lose even more weight?
大旋風吹き荒れろ
Let a great whirlwind blow
笑え明日も笑え
Smile, smile tomorrow too
ペコランダムの魔法
Pecorandom's magic
ペコランダム期待どおり
Pecorandom, just as expected
なんか　なんか　伝えたいばる
Somehow, somehow, I want to convey it
代われ代われ世界中
Change, change, all over the world
ちょっと　ちょっと　変えるために
Little by little, to change it
みんな　みんな　聞こえるか？
Everyone, everyone, can you hear me?
聞こえるかー！？
Can you hear me!?
ペコランダム　びっくりだわ
Pecorandom, I'm surprised
生きてりゃいいことあんぞ
If you're alive, good things will happen
災難災難のあとには
After misfortune, misfortune
楽しいことあるから
There will be fun things
ペコランダム　叫んじゃえば
Pecorandom, if I shout
人生はいいことあんぞ
In life, there are good things
大概この冷めた目と
Mostly with these cold eyes and
笑え泣いちゃうな笑え
Smile, don't cry, smile
ペコランダムの魔法
Pecorandom's magic
ペコランダム期待どおり
Pecorandom, just as expected
ペコランダムの魔法
Pecorandom's magic
ペコランダムはマママ　イェーイ！
Pecorandom is ma-ma-ma, yeah!
みんなー！
Everyone!
つ、ついに見えちゃってる、見えちゃってるぺこか？
Fi-Finally, can you see it? Can you see it, Peko?
あっ、やばい！
Ah, oh no!
見え... ぺこらの新しいお顔よ！
See... It's Pekora's new face!
どうぺこ？ぺこらのかわいくなったぺこかな？どう？
How is it? Did Pekora get cuter, Peko? How?
え、かわいくなった？
Eh, did I get cuter?
別人？ちょっと待ってよ、ちょっと、ちょっと誰よ！？
Someone else? Wait a minute, hey, who's that!?
コメントで、おっ、別人や、べ、ぺこなんでかわいく... かわいさを残しつつも、ちょっとね、あの、お化粧アップしていただきました！
The comments say, 'Whoa, you're a different person,' 'Peko, why so cute...' While keeping the cuteness, I had my makeup upgraded a bit!
ちょっと見て、いくよ、じゃあ、どんな顔になる？せーの、ぱっ！
Take a look. Here I go. What kind of face will I make? Ready, go!
あぁ。せーの、ぱっ！
Ah. Ready, go!
せーの、ぱっ！
Ready, go!
あははは！どうぺこか？
Ahahaha! How is it, Peko?
こんなね、表情も豊かになり、ちょっと髪の毛もちょっと、どうぺこ？このサラサラな感じにもなってね。
See, my expressions have become richer, and my hair a bit too, how is it, Peko? It's got this silky feel now.
そして、ぺこらのオリジナル曲、ペコランダムブレインを、このアップデートしたぺこらで歌わせて、そして踊らせていただいたぺこ！
And I sang and danced to my original song, Pecorandom Brain, with this updated Pekora, Peko!
かわいくなった！？ほんと！？やったやったやったー！ぺこだ！
Did I get cuter!? Really!? Yay, yay, yay! It's Peko!
いや、ちょっとさ、みんなになんて言われるかなと思ってたぺこだから、ちょっとあれだったんだけど、
I was a bit worried about what everyone would say, so I was a bit anxious, but,
でもね、実を言うと今日はね、ぺこらの生誕祭っていうことで、
but to tell you the truth, since today is Pekora's birthday festival,
ちょっとご褒美があるみたいぺこで、ぺこらの願いを叶えてくれた方々がいるみたいぺこなんです。
it seems there's a reward, Peko. It seems there are people who have granted Pekora's wish, Peko.
ちょっとみんなでその、VTRがあるみたいぺこだから、一緒にちょっと見てもらってもいいぺこか？
It seems there's a VTR of that, so can you watch it with me, Peko?
ぺこらも、今から初めて見るぺこだから、じゃあ、ぺこらご褒美企画行きたいと思います。
Pekora is seeing it for the first time now too, so let's go to the 'Pekora's Reward Project'.
じゃ大、VTRお願いします！
Well then, VTR please!
あれ？ぺこらのご褒美？
Eh? Pekora's reward?
2021年12月　都内某所
December 2021, Somewhere in Tokyo
はっ！きれいなお姉さんが、楽器を持っている！
Hah! A beautiful lady is holding an instrument!
兎田ぺこら　誕生日を祝うため…
To celebrate Usada Pekora's birthday...
あ、続々と人が来たぺこだ。
Ah, people are coming in one after another, Peko.
何が起きるぺこなの！？何が起きるの！？いや、ぺこら知ってるけど！
What's going to happen, Peko!? What's going to happen!? I mean, I know, but!
あははは！知ってるぺこだけど、何が起きてるぺこなの！？
Ahahaha! I know, but what on earth is happening, Peko!?
一夜限りのセッション
A one-night-only session
ちょっと、ちょっとシュール！あははは！
This is a bit, a bit surreal! Ahahaha!
もしかしてぺこらだけど、ぺこらの好きなあの曲をやってくれるぺこなんじゃないの！？
Maybe I'm just guessing, but aren't they going to play that song I like!?
もしかして！すごーい！
Could it be!? Amazing!
総勢３９名。
A total of 39 people.
奏でる曲は？
What song will they play?
やばい、ちょっと！39名！かな...
Oh my god! 39 people! What song...
総勢 39 名。奏でる曲は？
A total of 39 people. What song will they play?
何ペコは？
What's this, peko?
何？お友達ペコらのために...
What? For Pekora's friends...
えええ！
Whaaat!
やばい！
This is crazy!
待って、ペコら、ペコらいないよ。あ、嬉しい。
Wait, I'm not... I'm not in there. Ah, I'm so happy.
ペコらのためだけの序曲来た！
The overture just for Pekora is here!
うわ、やばい！
Wow, crazy!
今までゲームとかさ、ドラクエのパレードのさ、あれでさ、あの、聞いてきたペコだけど、
I've heard it in games and such, like at the Dragon Quest parade,
一度もペコらのための序曲は聞いたことなかったペコなの。
but I've never heard an overture just for Pekora before.
だから、ペコら...
That's why Pekora...
うるさい、ちょっとやめてよ。
Be quiet, cut it out for a second.
あ、ちょっと、分かるよ。
Ah, wait, I understand.
奇麗に言いたい... 待ってペコら！
I want to say something nice... Wait, Pekora!
え、待って、なんか映ってたよ今ペコら。
Oh, wait, I was just on the screen!
ペコらのためだけの序曲だよ、これは。
This is an overture just for Pekora.
こんな嬉しいことはないペコな。
I couldn't be happier, peko.
めっちゃめっちゃみんな真剣にやってくれてる。
Everyone is playing so seriously for me.
うわ、もう、今日このまま死んでもいいかもしれないぐらい嬉しいペコ。
Wow, I'm so happy I could die right now, peko.
しかもペコらがこれ載ってるのがちょっと、なんか俺は...
And the fact that I'm featured in this is just...
あ、ちょっと、あ、そうか。ちょっと静かに。
Ah, wait, ah, I see. Let's be quiet for a bit.
うわ、やば、慎んで聞いちゃうかもしれないペコ。
Wow, I might listen to this with reverence, peko.
あ、トライアングルや！
Oh, the triangle!
ペコらも、できるかな？隣でありたかったな。
I wonder if I could do that too? I wish I was there next to them.
え、すご。
Whoa, amazing.
あ、胸がいっぱいすぎる。
Ah, my heart is so full.
みんな、この39名一人ひとりペコらを思いながら吹いてくれたってことペコだよね。
All 39 of them were thinking of me while they played, right, peko?
後ろに、あれ、カジノの、あれ、やってるやつじゃないペコ？ちょっと空気読め、ペコだよ。後ろ。
Isn't that the casino scene playing in the back? Read the room, peko. The background.
せめてもうちょっとボスの戦いとかあったペコだろ。
They could have at least shown a boss battle or something, peko.
何でカジノであれやってるやつなんだよ。
Why are they showing the casino one?
いい。これ生で聞きたかったペコ。でも嬉しい。
So good. I wish I could've heard it live, peko. But I'm happy.
これ何度も聴けるってことペコだよな。
This means I can listen to it many times, right, peko?
ビデオがあるということは、聴きたい時にいつでも聴ける。
Since there's a video, I can listen to it whenever I want.
この子たち上手いな。
These kids are good.
後で、後で伝えるペコだけど。
I'll tell them later, peko.
当たり前だろ、バカタレが。
Well of course they are, you fool.
何言ってんだペコ。
What am I even saying, peko?
あ、ペコら指揮者やりたい。
Ah, Pekora wants to be the conductor.
いいわ、これ。ペコらの想像で...
This is nice. In my imagination...
あ、ペコらがなんか指揮者やってるみたいでめっちゃいいよ。
Ah, it looks like I'm the conductor, this is so cool.
はい、そこ強めに。優しくね。
Okay, stronger there. Gently now.
あ、優しく。
Ah, gently.
はい、はい、はい。
Yes, yes, yes.
終わりよ。
It's the end.
あ、いいよ、もっともっと。
Ah, it's good, more, more.
もっと！
More!
あ、今のも最高！ありが...
Ah, that was great too! Thank...
何？ドラクエ×ぺこ～ら。
What? Dragon Quest x Pekora.
ドラクエ × ぺこ～ら 去年は色々ありました。
Dragon Quest x Pekora. A lot happened last year.
去年は色々ありました。
A lot happened last year.
待って、自分のスライム出せんの！？
Wait, I can put out my own slime!?
せーの、スラりん！
Ready, go, Slalin!
頑張れ！頑張れ！
Good luck! Good luck!
画面外！画面外！
Off-screen! Off-screen!
寝るなよ！あんた負けてるよ、スラりん！
Don't sleep! You're losing, Slalin!
スリルを味わおうぜ、みんな。スリル！
Let's enjoy the thrill, everyone. Thrill!
来た！
It's here!
あ、ちょっと待って。
Ah, wait a minute.
ギャンブルに夢中になったり…
Getting hooked on gambling...
あの、好感度下がるような切り抜きやめてくれる？
Um, can you stop using clips that make people like me less?
いや、すげー嬉しいペコなんだけど。
I mean, I'm super happy, peko, but...
一文無しになることもありました。
There were times I went broke.
あの、こんなカジノにはまってるアイドル嫌ペコだろ。誰も推したくないペコだろ。
Who would want an idol who's addicted to the casino? No one would want to support me.
売れねーの？
I can't sell it?
売れねーの？ パパスの形見 嘘じゃ～ん
I can't sell it? Pankraz's keepsake. No way.
売れねーの、パパスの形見？嘘じゃん。
I can't sell it, Pankraz's keepsake? No way.
やめろ、ドラクエファンに...
Stop it, the Dragon Quest fans will...
やめてぺこなあ！やめろぺこなや！
Stop it peko! Stop it peko-na-ya!
バカたれ！
You idiot!
ちょっと待ってよ。だけど...
Wait a second. But...
テメエ！ビアンカに何しやがんだ！
You bastard! What are you doing to Bianca!
あんたぺこーらの仲間に入んな！
You, join Pekora's team!
あー！やったやった！(仲間に)入ったーぺこーら！
Ah! Yes, yes! They joined, Pekora!
きたぁ！やったやったやった！
It's here! Yes, yes, yes!
待って待って待って、仲間にする！
Wait, wait, wait, I'll make them an ally!
ブラウンお前がいてくれてよかった！マジで。
Brown, I'm glad you were here! Seriously.
お前と仲間になれてよかった。
I'm glad we became allies.
何エモくしてるぺこだよ。
Why are you getting all emotional, peko?
色々あったなぁ、ドラクエ5。ぺこーらがいてくれてよかった。
A lot has happened in DQ5. I'm glad Pekora was here.
ぺこらさん！
Pekora-san!
お誕生日！
Happy!
おめでとう！
Birthday!
あぁー！ありがとうございます！
Ahhh! Thank you so much!
えーレベル上がった！イェーイ！
Ehh, I leveled up! Yay!
まだある、まだあるんだ。なんか申し訳ないぺこ。いや...
There's more, there's still more. I feel a bit bad, peko. No...
本当にちょっと最後レベル上がったぺこなんだけど。
But I really did level up at the end there, peko.
え、いやーすごいうれしかったぺこで、本当にありがとうございます。
Ehh, well, I was just so happy peko, thank you so much.
さっきね、あの弾いてくださった方々は国立音楽大学の方々で。
The people who performed just now were from Kunitachi College of Music.
いや本当にもう、ぺこらのわがままに付き合っていただき...
Really, for going along with Pekora's selfishness...
本当にありがとうございます。とてつもなくうれしかった...もう本当...
Thank you so much. I was incredibly happy... just, really...
生きててよかったななんて本当に思うぺこです、マジで。
I truly feel that I'm glad to be alive, seriously peko.
いや最後レベルも上がったからね。今年もレベルアップして生きたいなと思うぺこです。
Well, my level went up at the end, too. I want to keep leveling up this year, peko.
そしてやばいね。ぺこらも、こんなに、もう喜んでもうこれで終わりでいいや、とか...
And man, this is crazy. I'm so happy that I could just end it here, but...
そんなことじゃねえぺこだからね。
It's not going to be like that, peko.
みんなが多分待っているであろう、コラボパート！
Next up is the part everyone's probably waiting for, the collaboration part!
行きたいぺこですか？コラボパート！
Do you want to see it, peko? The collaboration part!
どうよ？あんたたち気になりたぺこなんじゃないの、コラボパート。
How about it? Aren't you guys curious about the collaboration part, peko?
行きたいっしょ！
You want to see it, right!
もうね、早速行きましょうぺこですか。コラボパートもね。
Let's get right into it then, shall we? The collaboration part.
たくさん、たくさん、いやぺこらがあのお誘いした方々を呼んでいます。
I've invited many, many guests that Pekora personally reached out to.
そして、あのこれはね、コラボパートも事前に収録してあるので。
And, you see, the collaboration part was also pre-recorded.
あの安心して。ぺこらもね、ちょっと今の気持ちをリセットできるようにね。
So rest easy. It'll give me a chance to reset my emotions a bit, too.
でもすごいうれしかったな。
But I was really so happy.
ってわけで。じゃあ。
With that being said. Well then.
コラボパートへ、レッツゴー！
On to the collaboration part, let's go!
アーウィップした
Ah, whipped
ケーキのような街は
The town like a cake is
好き！雪！マジマジック！
Love! Snow! Real Magic!
空がくれる
Given by the sky
コンフェッティは
The confetti is
冬のフェスティバル 天使の羽衣を
A winter festival, angels' robes
チントンシャン 目の国へ
Chin-ton-shan, to the land of eyes
おてて振るの（ゴー！ゴー！ゴー！）
Waving my hands (Go! Go! Go!)
雪の汽車が
The snow train
街を駆け（チュ！チュ！チュ！）
Runs through the town (Chu! Chu! Chu!)
絵本みたいな景色を
A scenery like a picture book
しんぴり見せてあげるわ
I'll show it to you mystically
願い込めて呪文さあ
With a wish, a spell now
さあ！ 唱えて！
Now! Chant it!
三拝！
Pray!
A B C D ド・シ・ラ・シ・ラ・シ・シ
A B C D Do-Si-La-Si-La-Si-Si
マジカル・ミラクル・クルポッポ
Magical Miracle Kuru-poppo
アーウィップした
Ah, whipped
ケーキのような街は
The town like a cake is
好き！雪！マジマジック！
Love! Snow! Real Magic!
空がくれる
Given by the sky
コンフェッティは
The confetti is
冬のフェスティバル 天使の羽衣を
A winter festival, angels' robes
ライトアップした
Lighted up
七色の街は
The seven-colored town is
好き！雪！マジマジック！
Love! Snow! Real Magic!
子供でいられたら
If only I could stay a child
いいんだ
It would be fine
Ladies and Gentlemen
Welcome to Snow Peak
チントンタン 冷たい
Chin-ton-tan, the cold
季節が好きなまま
Season as I like it
アイスも魔法も
Both ice and magic
解けないように（チュ！チュ！チュ！）
May they never melt (Chu! Chu! Chu!)
ずっとこのままでいいの
I'm fine with staying like this forever
やっぱりドキドキしたい
But I still want my heart to race
未来求め呪文今
Seeking the future, a spell now
ほら！ 唱えて！
Look! Chant it!
三拝！
Pray!
1 2 3 4 水・木・金・土
1 2 3 4 Wed-Thu-Fri-Sat
マジカル・ミラクル・クルポッポ
Magical Miracle Kuru-poppo
ホップアップした
Hopped up
ウサギのような気分
Feeling like a rabbit
好き！雪！マジマジック！
Love! Snow! Real Magic!
ダイスキで
Because I love you so much
目を開けたら
If I open my eyes
思い通り遊んでいけるよ
I can go on playing as I wish
眩しい白に
In the dazzling white
染まるハート君に
My heart is dyed for you
好き！雪！マジマジック！
Love! Snow! Real Magic!
大人のふりなんていーじゃん！
Pretending to be an adult is fine!
今日の寒さも忘れるように
So that we forget today's cold
悩みだって悩みだって凍らせて消せる魔法力よ
It's a magical power that can freeze and erase even worries
ABC D楽ししららししマジカルミラクルクルポム
ABC D fun, Shi-La-La-Shi-Shi, magical miracle Kuru-Pom
ホイップしたケーキのような街はキッキマジマジ
The town, like a whipped cake, is Kikki Maji-Maji
空がくれるコンフェッティは冬のベール祝う天使の羽よ
The confetti from the sky is an angel's wing celebrating winter's veil
ライトアップしたオーロラ色の街はキッキマジマジ
The lit-up aurora-colored town is Kikki Maji-Maji
ずっともっといられたら
If only we could stay like this forever
Dream on!
It's time!
ぺこらお誕生日おめでとう！
Pekora, happy birthday!
ありがとうぺこー！
Thank you, peko!
さっきもうここのキメポーズでもうブルブルがすごかったんだけど
My trembling during that final pose just now was incredible.
難しいからねーもうブルブルしちゃうよ
It's hard, after all! It makes you tremble.
いやでもホントスバル先輩一緒に歌ってくれてありがとうございますありがとうございますぺこ
But really, Subaru-senpai, thank you so much for singing with me, thank you peko.
こっちこそ呼んでくれてありがとうすごい嬉しい
I'm the one who should thank you for inviting me. I'm so happy.
楽しかったぺこホントに
It was really fun, peko.
お、えーとなんかところでなんかずっと思ってたことあるんだけどさ今日
Oh, and by the way, there's something I've been thinking about all day today...
なんかお前変わった？
Did you change somehow?
え、え、なんか変わってますぺこら？
Eh? Eh? Did I change?
なんか変わってますぺこら？
...Did I change?
え、可愛い、何だその雌の顔は！
Whoa, cute! What's with that feminine look on your face?!
雌の顔って！
Feminine look?!
え、マジでスバル先輩ぺこらも元から女の子ぺこなんですけど
Seriously, Subaru-senpai, I've always been a girl, peko.
いやいやスバルの知ってるぺこらは「あーたし、やるよー！」って
No, no. The Pekora I know is like, "I'll do it!"
似てないぺこそんなんぺこらのモノマネ
That's not like me at all, that impression.
「あーたし、やるよー！」っていつも言ってるじゃんぺこら
But you're always saying, "I'll do it!", Pekora.
いやそんな、なんか、なんなのそんな怖い顔みたいに
No, I don't... why do you make such a scary face?
「あーたしぺこー」だよ「あーたし」って違うぺこでしょ
I say "It's me, peko." "I'll do it" is different, isn't it?
それは怖いのさっきのでも言ってること一緒じゃん
That was scary. But you said the same thing as before.
まあでもなんかすごい可愛くなったぺこら
Well, anyway, you've become really cute, Pekora.
本当ぺこ？え、じゃあなんか一緒にちょっとポーズ取らないぺこかな
Really, peko? Then, shall we strike a pose together?
え、いいの？
Wait, is it okay?
え、取りましょうぺこ
Yes, let's do it, peko.
イエーイ、イエーイ、お、イエーイ
Yay! Yay! Oh, yay!
え、なかなスバル先輩とかでツーショットってないぺこだからみんなちょっとスクショタイムなんぺこかな
It's rare for me and Subaru-senpai to take a photo together, so maybe it's screenshot time for everyone.
チャッチャッチャッチャッ
Click, click, click, click.
可愛い、本当に可愛いぺこで本当に
Cute! Really cute, peko. Truly.
え、ぺこらも本当に可愛くなった
Yeah, you've really become cute, Pekora.
そんな褒めたって何も出ないよ今日は、何も出ないぺこですよ
Even if you praise me that much, I've got nothing to give you today, peko.
出ないの？でも出ないの？ちょっと待ってよ
Nothing? Really nothing? Wait a minute.
ちょっと待ってよ、なんか出ると思って褒めてたぺこなんですか
Wait a minute, were you praising me thinking you'd get something?
まあちょっとありますねその説は、ちょっと
Well, that theory is somewhat true.
いやマジで泣かないでよ逆ギレ
Hey, don't actually cry! That's just being a sore loser.
でもなんかこうやってスバル先輩と２人でコラボってなかなかないぺこだから
But you know, a 1-on-1 collab with Subaru-senpai is quite rare, peko.
本当に今日なんか嬉しさもあれば緊張もありなんかまた２人でなんかやりませんかゲームとかさ
So today, I was both happy and nervous. Shall we do something together again, like a game?
え、しちゃっていいの？
Wait, is that okay?
しちゃいましょうよー
Let's do it!
やなぺこやなぺこ
Yanapeko, yanapeko!
そうなんか中々コラボは多人数が多かったぺこだから２人が本当に
Yeah, most collabs have been with many people, so just the two of us is really...
ないけど結構ペコスバなんかやって欲しいって言う人もいるみたいけど
It's rare, but it seems there are people who want to see Pekosuba do something.
じゃあどっちがねゲームの腕が上か見せつけてやります
Then, I'll show you which one of us is better at games!
結局勝負になるぺこさなのか、ぺこらだってあーたしやるよーって
So it ends up being a competition? I'll be like, "I'll do it!"
あーたしやるよーじゃねえぺこなんだよマジで
Stop with the "I'll do it!", seriously.
あ、でもね今日は本当にお誕生日おめでとうだよ
Ah, but really, happy birthday today.
ありがとうぺこ。やばいそろそろ夕日が沈む頃になってきたらしいから
Thank you, peko. Oh no, it seems the sun is about to set...
共々に一緒にあの夕日に向かって帰ろう
So let's head home together towards that sunset.
行くぞスバル先輩！
Let's go, Subaru-senpai!
ああ、オッケー、何何何これ？何この下り？
Ah, okay. What is this? What's with this skit?
よりも三成の腕には！
More than Sunsay's arms!
SAN値ピンチ！SAN値ピンチ！
SAN value pinch! SAN value pinch!
誰だ？邪魔するのはままならん
Who is it? Interfering is unacceptable.
誰だ？守り抜けままならん
Who is it? Protecting is unacceptable.
理性がちぎれる瞬間
The moment reason is torn apart
SAN値ピンチ！SAN値ピンチ！
SAN value pinch! SAN value pinch!
理性がぶっ飛ぶ瞬間
The moment reason flies away
あなたを逃がさない
I won't let you escape
逃がさない！
Won't let you escape!
そうだ！邪魔するなバイバイライフ
That's right! Don't interfere, bye-bye life.
居眠り食らわす物どもよ
You people who are dozing off
そうだ！諦めだバイバイライフ
That's right! Give up, bye-bye life.
お待ちかねの物どもよ
You people who have been waiting
うれしはずかしものどもよ
You happy and embarrassed beings
あの子欲しいよあげない
I want that girl, but I won't give her to you
かこめかこめ 宇宙一
Circle 'round, circle 'round, best in the universe
わたしの真後ろ
Right behind me
あの国旗タイム 無理矢理
Forcing that flag time
奪いたいのが 愛の本能さ
The instinct of love is wanting to take it away
待って待って やだやだやだ
Wait, wait, no, no, no
恋は カオスのしもべなり
Love is a servant of chaos
現れし 私は誰？
Who is the "I" that has appeared?
恋は カオスのしもべなり
Love is a servant of chaos
選ばれし 君の神ですよ
I am your chosen god
ラブを喰らって戦いながらね
While eating love and fighting
どこなんとか言っても 本当に本当に大好き
No matter what you say, I really, really love you
這い寄りますか？ 生のうねりに
Shall we slither? To the surge of life
幸ピンチ 幸ピンチ 幸ピンチ...
Sachi Pinchi! Sachi Pinchi! Sachi Pinchi!
誰々々々々 あいつは泡々ハート
Who, who, who, who, who, he has a bubbly heart
うれしはずかしものどもよ
You happy and embarrassed beings
誰々々々々 押し付けの泡々ハート
Who, who, who, who, who, a forced bubbly heart
はやりだしたいものどもよ
Beings who want to be trendy
認知が斜めの幸ピンチ
A slanted perception, Sachi Pinchi
略奪みたいだね 幸ピンチ
It's like plundering, Sachi Pinchi
認知が歪んだ幸ピンチ
A distorted perception, Sachi Pinchi
あなたを逃がさない
I won't let you get away
そうそうそうなんだ あいつは神々
That's right, that's right, he is divine
ぼうとく的だったものどもよ
Beings who were blasphemous
そうそうそうなんだ 無邪気な神々
That's right, that's right, innocent gods
むしがよすぎるものどもよ
Beings who are too selfish
あの子食べます ダメです
I'll eat that girl. You can't.
這い寄る 宇宙へ
Slithering to the universe
あの子食べます 悪夢です
I'll eat that girl. It's a nightmare.
酸いも甘いも 愛のバリエーション
Sour and sweet, variations of love
すぐすぐ 来て来て来て
Quickly, quickly, come, come, come
変な未来のニャルラトホテプ
The Nyarlathotep of a strange future
困らせて神話になれ
Trouble them and become a myth
変な未来のニャルラトホテプ
The Nyarlathotep of a strange future
愛すべき 君の神ですよ
I am your lovable god
混み合う女は見逃さないでしょ
You won't miss the crowded women, right?
どこなんとか言っても 本当にやっぱり大好き
No matter what you say, I really, after all, love you
這いよりました じゃあまた来週
I slithered. See you again next week.
幸ピンチ 幸ピンチ 幸ピンチ...
Sachi Pinchi! Sachi Pinchi! Sachi Pinchi!
恋は カオスのしもべなり
Love is a servant of chaos
現れし 私は誰？
Who is the "I" that has appeared?
恋は カオスのしもべなり
Love is a servant of chaos
選ばれし 君の神ですよ
I am your chosen god
変な未来のニャルラトホテプ
The Nyarlathotep of a strange future
困らせて神話になれ
Trouble them and become a myth
変な未来のニャルラトホテプ
The Nyarlathotep of a strange future
愛すべき 君の神ですよ
I am your lovable god
ラブを喰らって戦いながらね
While eating love and fighting
どこなんとか言っても 本当に本当に大好き
No matter what you say, I really, really love you
這い寄りますか？ 生のうねりに
Shall we slither? To the surge of life
はー！お疲れ様 ぺこらっちょ！
Phew! Good job, Pekoraccho!
えっ！？
Eh!?
えっ、何で？
Wait, why?
あの、えっ、何で？えっ、何で？呼び方...
Um, wait, why? Why did the name...
戻ったの。
It went back to how it was.
やだ、何で？戻ったって何、何があった？
No, why? What do you mean it went back? What happened?
心境の変化？ころさんって呼んでたじゃん。何で？
A change of heart? You were calling me Koro-san before. Why?
あんなに近づいてきたのにさ、何でそんな急に...
We had gotten so close, so why all of a sudden...
あ、あの、急にまた遠ざかるやん、何でなん？
Ah, wait, you're suddenly acting distant again, why?
あ、あの頃はもう覚えてないぺこ...
U-Um, I don't remember those times anymore, peko...
覚えてるぺこら。
You remember, Pekora.
覚えてるぺこら。せっかくころさんって呼んで...
You remember. After finally calling me Koro-san...
裏でもずっとコロねぇ先輩だったのに...
Even behind the scenes, it was always Korone-senpai...
やめてぺこ！いやあの時はちょっと、
Stop it, peko! Well, back then it was just,
あの、みんながころさんころさんって言うから、ぺこらもちょっと距離縮めようかなと思って、ころさんって...っ！
um, since everyone was saying Koro-san, I thought I'd try to shorten the distance a bit too, and said Koro-san...!
だってさ、いきなりコラボでころさんって呼び始めたからさ、気になるぺこじゃん！気になるぺこだよ！
Because you suddenly started calling me Koro-san in a collab, I was curious, peko! I was curious, peko!
いや、気になるにしてもさ、いつからころさんって呼んでるの？
But even if you're curious, since when have I been calling you Koro-san?
それは怖いぺこよ、普通に...普通に...これはやばい、距離の縮め方間違えた。
That's scary, peko, honestly... honestly... this is bad, I messed up how to shorten the distance.
あ、ごめん、そんなに気にしてたんだ。ごめん、ちょっと気にしてたんぺこ？
Ah, sorry, you were that worried about it. Sorry, you've been worried about it a bit, peko?
いいんだよぺこ。
It's okay, peko.
いいんだよ。じゃあもうこれからは、あの、こうやって面と向かってね、
It's fine. So from now on, well, since we've met like this face-to-face,
確認できたから、ころね先輩って呼んでいいよ。
and confirmed it, you can call me Korone-senpai.
じゃ、ころさんって言っていいってことぺこ？
Then, does that mean I can call you Koro-san, peko?
いいぺこよ。
It's okay, peko.
じゃあ、封印の儀を。
Then, let's have the sealing ceremony.
封印の儀？ちょっと待って封印の儀って何ぺこ！？ちょっと待って！
Sealing ceremony? Wait a minute, what's a sealing ceremony, peko!? Wait!
もう一生、ころね先輩というワードは出さないように、ここで、もう、儀式を。
So that you never utter the word "Korone-senpai" again for the rest of your life, here, a ceremony.
よし...
Alright...
じゃあ待ってるから呼んで。
Okay, I'm waiting, so call me.
OKぺこ。
Okay, peko.
じゃあもう今年からは、もうころね先輩とは言わなくて...
Then, starting this year, I won't say Korone-senpai anymore...
ころさん！
Koro-san!
ぺこら！
Pekora!
何ぺこれ！何ぺこれ！
What's this, peko! What's this, peko!
じゃあ、和解もしたところで...
Now that we've reconciled...
ということで、一枚撮りますか。
So, shall we take a picture?
あ、いいぺこね！
Oh, that's a good idea, peko!
あ、はい。
Oh, okay.
え、え、なにこのダサ... ダサくね、ぺこらちゃん。
What, what is this lame... Isn't it a bit lame, Pekora-chan?
撮れた？大丈夫？ちょっとドヤ顔のほうがいい？
Did you get it? Is it okay? Maybe a smug face would be better?
あ、ドヤ顔にしよ、ぺこ。
Ah, let's do a smug face, peko.
撮れた？
Did you get it?
イエーイ！
Yay!
あー、いいんじゃない？
Ah, looks good, doesn't it?
じゃ、じゃあ、これからも歩んでいくから。
Well, then, since we'll keep walking forward from here on.
これからも...！
From here on...!
じゃあ一緒にいこうぺこ！
Then let's go together, peko!
あ、じゃあ準備を。
Ah, then let's get ready.
ラ、ラ、ラ... コン様！
La, la, la... Noel-sama!
ぺこら！
Pekora!
サイレントマジョリティー
作詞：秋元康 作曲：バグベア
Silent Majority
Lyrics: Yasushi Akimoto / Composition: Bugbear
人が溢れた交差点を どこへ行く？
Where are you going at the crowded intersection?
（押し流され）
(Swept away)
似たような服を着て 似たような表情で
Wearing similar clothes, with similar expressions
群れの中に紛れるように歩いてる
Walking as if to blend into the crowd
（疑わずに）
(Without doubt)
誰かと違うことに 何を躊躇うのだろう
Why do you hesitate to be different from someone else?
（いつの間にか）
(Before you know it)
先行く人が振り返り
The person ahead looks back
列を乱すなと
Saying "don't break the line"
ルールを説くだけの その目は死んでいる
Those eyes that only preach rules are dead
君は君らしく生きて行く自由があるんだ
You have the freedom to live as yourself
大人たちに支配されるな
Don't be controlled by adults
初めからそう諦めてしまったら
If you give up like that from the start
僕らは何のために生まれたのか？
What were we born for?
夢を見ることは時には孤独にもなるよ
Dreaming sometimes makes you lonely
誰もいない道を進むんだ
Go down the path where no one else is
この世界は群れていても始まらない
This world won't start even if we're in a crowd
YESでいいのか？ サイレントマジョリティー
Is 'YES' okay? Silent Majority
どこかの国の 大統領が言っていた
A president of some country said
（曲解して）
(Misinterpreting)
声を上げない者たちは 賛成していると
That those who do not speak up are in agreement
（あやふやに）
(Vaguely)
選ぶことが大事なんだ 人に任せるな
Choosing is important, don't leave it to others
（自分勝手）
(Selfishness)
行動しなければ Noと伝わらない
If you don't act, 'NO' won't be conveyed
君は君らしくやりたいことをやるだけさ
Just do what you want to do, as yourself
ワン・オブ・ゼムに成り下がるな
Don't settle for being just 'one of them'
ここにいる人の数だけ道はある
There are as many paths as there are people here
自分の夢の方に歩けばいい
You just have to walk towards your own dream
見栄やプライドの鎖に繋がれたような
Like being bound by the chains of appearance and pride
つまらない大人は置いて行け
Leave the boring adults behind
さあ未来は君たちのためにある
Come, the future is there for you
Noと言いなよ サイレントマジョリティー
Say 'NO', Silent Majority
誰かの後 ついて行けば 傷つかないけど
If you follow behind someone, you won't get hurt
（その群れが）
(That crowd)
総意だと ひとまとめにされる
Will be treated as a single consensus
君は君らしく生きて行く自由があるんだ
You have the freedom to live as yourself
大人たちに支配されるな
Don't be controlled by adults
初めからそう諦めてしまったら
If you give up like that from the start
僕らは何のために生まれたのか？
What were we born for?
夢を見ることは時には孤独にもなるよ
Dreaming sometimes makes you lonely
誰もいない道を進むんだ
Go down the path where no one else is
この世界は群れていても始まらない
This world won't start even if we're in a crowd
YESでいいのか？ サイレントマジョリティー
Is 'YES' okay? Silent Majority
我らは、せーの！
We are, one, two!
ペットボトル〜！
Pet Bottles!
あ、いいぺこじゃん、なんか。
Oh, that was good, somehow.
な、なんのことしてるぺこなの、みんな？
W-What are you all doing, peko?
え、かっこいいポーズ。
Eh, a cool pose.
かっこいいポーズ？あ、なんかるーちゃんと似てる。あ、似てる！いいえ！るーちゃん、それなあに？
A cool pose? Oh, it's kind of like Ru-chan's. Oh, it is! Nice! Ru-chan, what's that?
え、これ、かっこいいポーズ。
Eh, this is a cool pose.
可愛いだわ、一応、でも。
It's cute, mostly, but.
あ、私ペットボトル、ペットボトルの形しないといけないぺこでしょ？
Ah, I'm a Pet Bottle, so I have to make a Pet Bottle shape, right?
え、ペットボトルの形？
Eh, a Pet Bottle shape?
ペットボトルの形、これ、これ。
A Pet Bottle shape, this, this.
これが？
This?
え、これがぺこでしょ？いいぺこじゃん、いいぺこじゃん。
Eh, this is it, peko, right? It's good, peko, it's good.
じゃ、我らは、我らはペットボトル。
Then, we are, we are Pet Bottles.
いいぺこじゃん、ちょっとダサい、ダサいかな？
It's good, peko, although it's a bit lame, is it lame?
あ、可愛くないぺこ？これ、足上げたら。
Oh, isn't it cute, peko? If I lift my leg like this.
ほら、みんなペットボトルポーズ。よし！どう？
Look, everyone, Pet Bottle pose. Alright! How is it?
あ、いいじゃんいいじゃん！可愛い可愛い！
Oh, it's good, it's good! Cute, cute!
いや、そんなことよりさ、うわー、今日、ダサ！ダサ！
No, more importantly, wow, today, so lame! So lame!
誰だよこれ？
Who even is this?
あ、今日、今日は、そう、今日は、ぺこらの生誕祭に来てくれて、本当にありがとうございますぺこな。
Ah, today, today, yes, today, thank you so much for coming to Pekora's birthday celebration, peko.
いえいえ！どういたしまして！
No problem! You're welcome!
すごい、すごい、ぺこ、ぺこ。
Amazing, amazing, peko, peko.
なんか、四人でさ、歌えたの、本当にぺこらちょっとね、嬉しくて。
Somehow, being able to sing with the four of us, Pekora is really a bit happy.
なんかかんかさ、最近、コラボとかも四人でやってたりもしたぺこだからさ。
One way or another, we've been doing collabs as a group of four lately, peko.
なんか、嬉しかったな。今日。ありがとうぺこな。本当にね。
Somehow, I'm glad. Today. Thank you, peko. Truly.
あ、楽しかったね。楽しかった。
Ah, it was fun. It was fun.
とわちゃん、イェーイ！イェーイ！
Towa-chan, yay! Yay!
ぺこら誕生日なのに、ちょっと... もう一回やろう。
Even though it's Pekora's birthday, wait... let's do it again.
やべ、ぺこらのとこ、行くわ。
Crap, I'm going over to Pekora.
うわ、すごいじゃん！
Whoa, that's amazing!
なになに、このポーズ！
What, what is this pose!
わあ、いいペコじゃん！
Wow, it's good, peko!
入れ替わろう。
Let's swap places.
乗っとる、乗っとる気持ちでカメラの前に。
I'm taking over, coming in front of the camera with a takeover mindset.
そうだね。
That's true.
いや、乗っとる、ぺこらの生誕祭だぞ、するぺこだぞ。
No, I'm taking over, it's Pekora's birthday celebration, I'm doing it, peko.
そんな、そんな！
No way, no way!
いや、本当わちゃわちゃが凄すぎて、ぺこ可愛すぎでしょ、マジで。
No, the chaos is just too much, Pekora is too cute, seriously.
な、でもなんかいい感じじゃない？ペットボトルっぽいよね。
But, isn't it kind of good? It looks like a Pet Bottle.
だね。
True.
なんかね、このわちゃわちゃがいいぺこだから、なんかまた集まりたいぺこだね。違うことでもな。
Somehow, this chaos is good, peko, so I want to gather again, peko. Even for something different.
本当？また呼んでもらえるってこと？
Really? Does that mean we'll be invited again?
やべー、決まってるぺこ。みんなも呼んでぺこだよ。
Heck yeah, it's a given, peko. Everyone, call for us, peko.
いいよ。
Sure.
あれ、黙ってる？
Wait, are you quiet?
とわちゃん、あれ？とわちゃん？
Towa-chan, huh? Towa-chan?
お、嫌なの？ペットボトルが嫌なの？
Oh, do you hate it? Do you hate the Pet Bottle?
とわちゃんが怖い。るしあちゃんととわちゃんが一番怖い。
Towa-chan is scary. Rushia-chan and Towa-chan are the scariest.
なんでよー！圧を感じないで、ぺこちゃん、圧を。
Why~! Don't feel the pressure, Peko-chan, the pressure.
ぺこちゃん。じゃ、ボタンちゃんぺこらたち、鍋食べに行かない？
Peko-chan. Then, Botan-chan and us, shall we go eat hot pot?
鍋行く？
Go for hot pot?
待って、待って！ぺこちゃん！
Wait, wait! Peko-chan!
せっかくさ、ペットボトルになったんだからさ、もっと喋ろうよ。
Since we finally became Pet Bottles, let's talk more.
行くよ、みんなで、鍋行こう。みんなで鍋行こう。
Let's go, everyone, let's go for hot pot. Let's go for hot pot together.
行きたい行きたい！
I want to go! I want to go!
あ、でもぺこらまだライブある、ごめん。
Ah, but Pekora still has a live show, sorry.
えっ！？嘘でしょ！？
What!? No way!?
USADA PEKORA BIRTHDAY LIVE
with gratitude
愛言葉Ⅲ
作詞 作曲：DECO*27
Ai Kotoba III
Lyrics & Composition: DECO*27
想い出の冒険を
The adventure of memories,
忘れずに全部言えるかな
I wonder if I can say it all without forgetting.
君から聴きたいよ
I want to hear it from you.
何回目の僕に出会った？
Which version of me did you meet?
僕は変わりました
I have changed,
新しい君に出会うために
in order to meet the new you.
久しぶりだね
It's been a while,
言えなかった言葉、ここで泣こうか
the words I couldn't say, shall we cry them out here?
好きとか嫌いとか
Like or dislike,
何度だって愛を歌う君が
you, who sings of love over and over again,
恋しくて嘘じゃない本当だよ
I missed you, it's not a lie, it's the truth.
また出会おう
Let's meet again.
僕ら二度嫌って
We hate each other twice,
三度に戻って
return for the third time,
何回だって
no matter how many times,
間違って来たいよ
I want to keep making mistakes.
三、五、六、七と
Three, five, six, seven,
冷めない愛情が
this love that never cools down
今夜はずっとループ
is looping all night long.
ほら二度嫌って
Look, hate each other twice,
また二に戻って
return back to two again,
三になって
become three,
愛を繋いでいこう
and let's connect our love.
見た感情は
The emotions I saw,
伝えたい世界は
the world I want to convey,
たった一つだけ
there's only one thing,
「ありがとう」
“Thank you.”
想い出の冒険は
The adventure of memories
これからもちゃんと続いていく
will continue properly from now on.
三と九に乗って
Riding on three and nine,
言葉とか飛び越えちゃって
jumping over words and such.
君も変わりました
You have changed too,
新しい誰かに会うために
in order to meet someone new.
大人になりました
I have become an adult,
それだけでいいと思えた
I felt that was enough.
手を繋いで
Hand in hand,
どこかへ
To somewhere,
ってなんて
Or something like that...
何度だって愛を歌うよ
I'll sing of love time and time again.
君が恋しくて
I miss you so much,
嘘じゃない 本当だよ
It's no lie, it's the truth.
また出会おう
Let's meet again.
Ooh, yeah!
恋をして
Falling in love,
馬鹿！
You idiot!
安心をして
Feeling at ease,
馬鹿！
You idiot!
馬鹿で
For being an idiot,
いいのさ
It's okay.
君をずっと
I'll always,
このまま
Be like this with you.
馬鹿！
You idiot!
僕らは1を嫌って
We hated "1",
2も取って
And took "2" as well.
何回だって
No matter how many times,
間違っていたいよ
I want to keep making mistakes.
限界突破
Breaking through the limits,
つたい愛情が
The love being transmitted,
今、リズムを刻む
Is now beating a rhythm.
ほら1を嫌って
Look, hating "1",
また2も取って
Taking "2" again.
3になって
Becoming "3",
愛を伝え行こう
Let's go share our love.
痛い感情も
Even painful feelings,
正解はたった一つだけ
There's only one correct answer.
ありがとう
Thank you.
もみくちゃになっていたいよ
I want to be all mixed up with you.
終わんない愛をあげたくないの
I don't want to give up this unending love.
もっとちゃんと話してよ
Talk to me more properly.
猛、感傷、代償、恋愛
Fierce sentiment, compensation, romance.
愛を抱いて
Embracing love,
理想を掲げて
Holding our ideals high.
行き場のない愛のメロディを
A melody of love with nowhere to go.
これまでありがとう
Thank you for everything so far.
いつまでも君と
Forever with you,
こんな歌あたためて
Keeping a song like this warm.
出会いを
So that I can,
数えられるように
Count our encounters.
あーーー！はい、みんなーーー！
Ahhh! Yes, everyone!
ふぅ、ちょっと移動させてもらいます。ふぅ。
Phew, let me move a bit. Phew.
みんな、どぺこー！
Hi everyone, do-peko!
合言葉Ⅲ、そして、コラボパートも楽しんでいただけたぺこか？
Did you enjoy 'Aigo III' and the collaboration part, peko?
可愛すぎる！ありがとぺこなー。ありがとぺこなー。
So cute! Thank you, peko. Thank you, peko.
いやでも、もうライブも終盤。そして、今日は告知を3つ、させていただきたいなと、思います！
But the live is already in its final stages. And today, I have three announcements to make!
まずはちょっと、1つ目の告知、いきたいなと、思います！
First, I'll go with the first announcement!
1つ目は、こちら！どぅるるる... どぅん！
The first one is... this! Drumroll... Ta-da!
兎田ぺこら 誕生日記念 2022
1月12日 販売開始
誕生日記念フルセット
・アクリルジオラマスタンド
・ラバーマット＆カードスリーブ
・ぺこらんどお札メモ＆ボールペン
・野うさぎぬいぐるみ
誕生日記念フルセット購入特典
憂姫はぐれ先生描き下ろしポストカード
(箔押し複製サイン＆メッセージ入り)
Usada Pekora Birthday Memorial 2022
On sale from Jan 12
Birthday Memorial Full Set
- Acrylic Diorama Stand
- Rubber Mat & Card Sleeves
- Pekoland Banknote Memo & Ballpoint Pen
- Nousagi Plushie
Birthday Memorial Full Set Purchase Bonus
Postcard drawn by Yuki Hagure-sensei
(With foil replica signature & message)
兎田ぺこら誕生日記念2022のグッズが、発売となります！イェーイ！
Usada Pekora's Birthday Memorial 2022 goods are going on sale! Yay!
こちらね、フルセット、ございます。
We have the full set here.
そして、フルセットのね、購入特典には、なんと、なんと、なんと、なんと！
And the bonus for the full set is, amazingly...
メッセージやサインが入った、あの、憂姫はぐれ先生の描き下ろしポストカードがついております！
A postcard drawn by Yuki Hagure-sensei with a message and signature!
こちらね、可愛いぺこ！メッセージは届いてからのお楽しみにということで。
It's so cute, peko! Please look forward to the message after it arrives.
けど、けど！「ちょっとフルセット買えないよ」「ちょっとお小遣いが...」っていう人のために、単品も用意してございます！
But! For those who can't get the full set or are short on money, we have individual items too!
それが、こちら！どぅん！
And those are... these! Ta-da!
アクリルジオラマスタンド
イラスト 憂姫はぐれ
サイズ 組み立て時：約H137.5×W163.5×D63mm
素材：アクリル
Acrylic Diorama Stand
Illustration: Yuki Hagure
Size (Assembled): Approx. H137.5×W163.5×D63mm
Material: Acrylic
まずは1つ目は、アクリルジオラマスタンド！
First is the Acrylic Diorama Stand!
こちらポストカードのイラストと同じぺこなんですが、はぐれ先生に描き下ろしで描いていただき、
It uses the same illustration as the postcard, newly drawn by Hagure-sensei.
ぺこランドのお城の中、ぺこちゃんの、ま、実家というか、ま、お椅子みたいな感じのジオラマスタンド！
It's a diorama stand of Pekoland Castle, Peko-chan's home, or like her chair!
そして！
And!
こちらなんと、ラバーマット＆カードスリーブ！イラストは、さいとうなおき先生ぺこです！
This is a Rubber Mat & Card Sleeves! Illustrated by Saito Naoki-sensei, peko!
ラバーマット＆カードスリーブ
イラスト さいとうなおき
サイズ：ラバーマット：約H34×W60cm
カードスリーブ：約H92×W67mm
枚数：1パック 60枚入り
素材：ラバーマット：ポリエステル・天然ゴム
カードスリーブ：表：OPP+VMCP　裏：OPP+CPP
Rubber Mat & Card Sleeves
Illustration: Saito Naoki
Size: Mat: Approx. H34×W60cm
Sleeves: Approx. H92×W67mm
Quantity: 60 per pack
Material: Mat: Polyester, Natural Rubber
Sleeves: Front: OPP+VMCP, Back: OPP+CPP
いや、こちら本当にもう、ぺこら、嬉しくて嬉しくて嬉しくて、たまらないぺこなんですけども、
I'm just so happy about this, I can't stand it, peko.
ぜひね、カードやってる方々には、使っていただきたいなと。ぺこらも机にさ、ラバーマットやって、なんか、ぺこのお気に入りのカードとか入れちゃおうかなって思うので、
I'd love for card game players to use them. I'll use the mat on my desk and put my favorite cards in the sleeves too.
ぜひ皆さん、ね、ぺこらとお揃いにして、いただけたらななんて思います。
So I hope everyone gets the same set as me.
そして、もう1つが、こちら！どぅん！
And one more, this! Ta-da!
ぺこらんどお札メモ＆ボールペン
サイズ：お札メモ：約H76×W145mm (40枚綴り)
ボールペン：約141×W12mm (インク色：黒・油性)
素材：お札メモ：紙・PP
ボールペン：ABS樹脂・鉄 (文具雑貨)
Pekoland Banknote Memo & Ballpoint Pen
Size: Memo: Approx. H76×W145mm (40 sheets)
Pen: Approx. 141×W12mm (Ink: Black, Oil-based)
Material: Memo: Paper, PP
Pen: ABS resin, Iron (Stationery)
なんと、ぺこらんどのお札メモ＆ボールペン！
Believe it or not, a Pekoland Banknote Memo Pad & Ballpoint Pen!
なんと、今回ね、ちょっと、本物のぺこランドのお金は、あの、ちょっと、用意できないぺこなんですけども、
I couldn't prepare real Pekoland money this time, peko.
ま、メモ帳としてね、こういうお札使ってますよーっていうメモ帳と、ま、それに付け加えたボールペン、付けさせていただいております。
But I've made a memo pad designed like our banknotes, along with a ballpoint pen.
ぜひね、なんか、おうちに一個あったら安心するんじゃないぺこかなーって、思いますぺこ。ですので、ぜひぜひお買い求めください！
I think having one at home would be reassuring, peko. So please, go ahead and buy it!
そして、もう1つが、こちら！どぅん！
And one more, this! Ta-da!
野うさぎぬいぐるみ
サイズ：約H45.7×W39×D30.2cm
素材：ポリエステル・ポリウレタン
Nousagi Plushie
Size: Approx. H45.7×W39×D30.2cm
Material: Polyester, Polyurethane
なんと、野うさぎのぬいぐるみ！
Wow, a Nousagi plushie!
こちら、高さ、約45.7cm、横が39cmという、とてつもなく大きいぬいぐるみとなっております。ぜひ、一家に一台は！
It's a massive plushie, about 45.7cm tall and 39cm wide. One for every home!
野うさぎぬいぐるみ
サイズ：約H45.7×W38×D36.2cm
素材：ポリエステル・ポリウレタン
Nousagi Plushie
Size: Approx. H45.7×W38×D36.2cm
Material: Polyester, Polyurethane
嬉しー。一家に一台は欲しいと思いますぺこらですので、
I'm so happy. I think every household needs one, since it's Pekora,
ぜひ、ぜひ、ぜひ、お買い求めいただけたらなと思います。
so please, please, please buy one!
そして今回のグッズぺこなんですけども、
Also, regarding this merchandise...
大変申し訳ございません。
I am very sorry.
ちょっとね、ぺこらの不手際で、えっとこちらのグッズ販売...
Due to a mistake on my part, the sales for this merchandise...
日本の方は10時、この配信が終わった後にすぐ買えるぺこなんですけど、
People in Japan can buy it at 10:00, right after this stream ends,
海外ニキルぺこ、海外！
but for overseas fans—overseas!
I'm sorry, sorry.
海外ニキの方は10時10分、あの日本時間の10時10分...
For overseas fans, it's 10:10... 10:10 PM Japan time.
あの10分ちょっと遅れちゃうけど、でも安心！
It's delayed by about 10 minutes, but don't worry!
全員買えるぺこですから。
Everyone will be able to buy it.
あの限定の商品など一切ございません。買いたい方は全員買えますので。
There are no limited-edition items. Everyone who wants one can buy one.
安心してね。ちょっと10分遅れちゃって申し訳ないぺこだけど、
Rest assured. I'm sorry for the 10-minute delay,
安心してお買い求めいただけたらなと思います。
but please feel free to make your purchase.
そして告知2つ目はこちら！
And the second announcement is this!
本日10時半から、えっとアンコールメンバー限定のライブがございます！
At 10:30 PM today, there'll be a members-only encore live!
メンバー限定アンコールLIVE
Members-Only Encore LIVE
こちらね、メンバー限定のアンコールライブが10時半から行いたいと思いますので、
I'll be doing a members-only encore live from 10:30 PM,
ぜひぜひ、あのメンバーの方、そして今から入ってくださる方も楽しんでいただけたらなと思います。
so I hope members and those who join now will enjoy it.
よろしくお願いいたします。頑張るぺこですので。よろぺこな。
I'll do my best, so thank you! Yoropeko!
あ、喜んでくれて嬉しいぺこなの。
Ah, I'm glad you're happy!
そして、多分最後のが一番みんな楽しみに待っててくれたのかな？
And now, the one you've probably been waiting for the most?
告知3つ目、行っちゃっていいぺこですか？
Can I share the third announcement?
なんと！兎田ぺこら、
Wait for it! Usada Pekora's
オリ曲2曲目を、リリース決定！
second original song is being released!
ジャジャーン！
Ta-da!
その名も「いいわけバニー」！
The title is 'Excuse Bunny'!
このあと、みんな聴きたいぺこですか？これ。聴きたいぺこですか？
Do you guys want to hear it after this? Do you want to hear it?
聴きたい？
Do you?
こちらもね、あのこのあとお披露目もしたいぺこなんですけども、
I'd like to perform it now, but...
24時、本日の24時にあの配信も開始されるので、
it will also be available on streaming services at midnight today,
ぜひとも皆さんたくさん聴いていただけたらなと思います！
so I hope everyone listens to it a lot!
じゃあ、そろそろ新曲行ってもいいぺこですか？
Now, shall we get to the new song?
いいぺこですよね。聴きたい。
Is that okay? You want to hear it.
オッケオッケ。
Okay, okay.
それじゃあ、行っちゃいますか。
Well then, let's do this.
新曲、「いいわけバニー」。
New song, 'Excuse Bunny'.
どっちが好きなのよ
Which one do you like?
いいわけバニー
作詞：岩見陸 作曲：ナナホシ管弦楽団
Excuse Bunny
Lyrics: Riku Iwami / Music: Nanahoshi Orchestra
なんとかなんないかな
Can't we do something?
隣のあいつが邪魔だね
That guy next to me is in the way.
いーくない？そんなこと
Isn't that bad? Thinking that.
正々堂々絶対
Fair and square, absolutely.
他とは違うな
It's different from the others.
なんだか競争
It's like a competition.
苦手だそうゆうの
I'm not good at that kind of thing.
なんどかさみしいもしもしもし
It's somewhat lonely... Hello, hello, hello.
目指しちゃってペーパレードしちゃった
I aimed for it and went on a parade.
あの子に負けない誰だってジェラシー
I won't lose to her. Everyone's jealous.
よくばりね独り占めしたいです
Greedy, right? I want you all to myself.
言わなきゃわかってどー
Understand it without me having to say it.
あーでもないこーでもない
Neither this nor that.
夢にしましょう
Let's make it a dream.
つらぬけ My my my mind
Stick to it, my my my mind.
聞きたくない いいわけバニー
I don't want to hear it, Excuse Bunny.
地団駄の 猶予だだんだん
Stamping feet, gradually running out of time.
バニーバニーバニー待ちぼうけの話
Bunny bunny bunny, a story of waiting in vain.
どっちが好きなのよ
Which one do you like?
よそ見しないで
Don't look away.
もうひげ出しちゃいたいのは私の方
The one who wants to let it all out is me.
邪魔しません反対方向
I won't get in the way, going the other way.
Want it いいわけバニー
Want it, Excuse Bunny.
大都会は大得意？
Are you good with big cities?
興味がねーから超ニガテ
I have no interest, so I'm super bad at it.
ひとごみに潜り出すハニー
Honey dives into the crowd.
届けて意気込み
Deliver your enthusiasm.
知った私なり 荒ぶってそーに
In my own way, as if acting wildly.
散弾 延長戦 叩くじゃバイバイバイ
Shotgun, overtime, clapping then bye-bye-bye.
精神あるのみ 荒ぶってエネミー
Only spirit remains, acting wild as an enemy.
絶頂だ アンタたち やっちまいなさい！
It's the climax! You guys, go for it!
疲れちゃった日 お休み
Rest on days you're tired.
なんとかなるよ やってよね
It'll work out. Do it.
明日の私 待たせろ My my my mind
Make my future self wait, my my my mind.
決められない いいわけバニー
Can't decide, Excuse Bunny.
うやむやへ 注意合図トットットッ
Towards vagueness, warning signal tot-tot-tot.
メニメニマニマニ 勝ち目の話
Many many money money, a story of winning odds.
落とし前です
It's a settlement.
大試し前です
It's before the big test.
そんなのってないわ 私一途な本調子
No way, I'm in my earnest top form.
My sweet 逃がさない
My sweet, I won't let you escape.
どこへだって行けばいい
Go wherever you want
言い訳なんて
No more excuses
しなーい
I won't make them
今日なんじゃなーい
Not today
ぶつけろ
Let it out
My My My My
聞きたくない
I don't want to hear it
いいわけバニー
Excuse Bunny
地団駄の
Stomping my feet
優柔不断さ
In indecision
バニバニダリダリ
Bunny-bunny Dari-dari
まやかしの話
A story of deception
どっち？ どっち？
Which one? Which one?
大好きなのよ
I love you so much
ダメダメダメ
No, no, no
よそ見しないで
Don't look away
ダメダメダメ
No, no, no
逃げ出したーい
I want to run away
けどやるしかない
But I have to do it
正真正銘
Pure and simple
反対方向
In the opposite direction
One! WANTED!
WANTED!
ONLY ALIVE
USADA PEKORA
$111,111,000
言い訳バニー
Excuse Bunny
そばにいて
Stay by my side
言い訳バニー
Excuse Bunny